Hello, it's me
I was wondering if after all
these years you'd like to meet
To go over everything
They say that time's supposed to heal ya
But I ain't done much healing
Hello, can you hear me?
I'm in California dreaming
about who we used to be
When we were younger and free
I've forgotten how it felt
before the world fell at our
feet
There's such a difference between us
And a million miles
Hello from the other side
I must have called a thousand times
To tell you I'm sorry for
everything that I've done
But when I call you never seem
to be home
Hello from the outside
At least I can say that I've tried
To tell you I'm sorry for
breaking your heart
But it don't matter. It
clearly doesn't tear you apart
anymore
Hello, how are you?
It's so typical of me to talk
about myself. I'm sorry
I hope that you're well
Did you ever make it out of
that town where nothing ever
happened?
And it's no secret that the both of us
Are running out of time
So hello from the other side (
other side)
I must have called a thousand
times (thousand times)
To tell you I'm sorry for
everything that I've done
But when I call you never seem
to be home
Hello from the outside (outside)
At least I can say that I've
tried (I've tried)
To tell you I'm sorry for
breaking your heart
But it don't matter. It
clearly doesn't tear you apart
anymore
(Highs, highs, highs, highs,
Lows, lows, lows, lows)
Anymore
(Highs, highs, highs, highs,
Lows, lows, lows, lows)
Anymore
(Highs, highs, highs, highs,
Lows, lows, lows, lows)
Anymore
(Highs, highs, highs, highs,
Lows, lows, lows, lows)
Anymore
Hello from the other side (other side)
I must have called a thousand
times (thousand times)
To tell you I'm sorry for
everything that I've done
But when I call you never seem
to be home
Hello from the outside (outside)
At least I can say that I've
tried (I've tried)
To tell you I'm sorry for
breaking your heart
But it don't matter. It
clearly doesn't tear you apart
anymore
www.RentAnAdviser.com