Oh, her eyes, her eyes make
the stars look like they're
not shining
Her hair, her hair falls
perfectly without her trying
She's so beautiful
And I tell her everyday.
Yeah, I know, I know when I
compliment her, she won't
believe me
And it's so, it's so sad to
think that she doesn't see
what I see
But every time she ask me do I
look okay?
I say
When I see your face
There's not a thing that I would change
'Cause you're amazing
Just the way you are
And when you smile
The whole world stops and
stares for a while
'Cause girl, you're amazing
Just the way you are
Her lips, her lips, I could
kiss them all day if she'd let
me
Her laugh her laugh, she hates
but I think it's so sexy
She's so beautiful
And I tell her everyday
Oh, you know, you know, you
know I'd never ask you to
change
If perfect's what you're
searching for, then just stay
the same
So don't even bother asking if
you look okay
You know I'll say
When I see your face
There's not a thing that I would change
'Cause girl you're amazing
Just the way you are
And when you smile
The whole world stops and
stares for a while
'Cause girl, you're amazing
Just the way you are
The way you are
Girl, you're amazing
Just the way you are
When I see your face
There's not a thing that I would change
'Cause girl you're amazing
Just the way you are
And when you smile
The whole world stops and
stares for a while
'Cause girl, you're amazing
Just the way you are.
Yeah
www.RentAnAdviser.com