Am I wrong
For thinking out the box from
where I stay?
Am I wrong
For saying that I choose another way?
I ain't trying to do what
everybody else doin'
Just 'cause everybody doin'
what they all do
If one thing I know,
I'll fall but I'll grow
I'm walking down this road of
mine, this road that I call
home
So am I wrong?
For thinking that we could be
something for real?
Now am I wrong?
For trying to reach the things
that I can't see?
But that's just how I feel,
That's just how I feel
Trying to reach the things
that I can't see
Am I tripping
For having a vision?
My prediction
I'ma be on the top of the world
Walk your walk and don't look back,
Always do what you decide
Don't let them control your life,
that's just how I feel oh whoa
Fight for yours and don't let go,
Don't let them compare you, no
Don't worry, you're not alone,
that's just how we feel
Am I wrong? (am I wrong?)
For thinking that we could be
something for real?
(Oh yeah yeah yeah yeah, oh)
Now am I wrong? (am I wrong?)
For trying to reach the things
that I can't see?
(Oh yeah yeah yeah yeah, yeah)
That's just how I feel,
Trying to reach the things
that I can't see
If you tell me I'm wrong, wrong
I don't wanna be right, right
I don't wanna be right
If you tell me I'm wrong, wrong
I don't wanna be right, right
I don't wanna be right
Am I wrong?
For thinking that we could be
something for real?
Now am I wrong?
For trying to reach the things
that I can't see?
But that's just how I feel,
But that's just how I feel
That's just how I feel
Trying to reach the things
that I can't see
So am I wrong? (am I wrong?)
For thinking that we could be
something for real?
(Oh yeah yeah yeah yeah, oh)
Now am I wrong? (am I wrong?)
For trying to reach the things
that I can't see?
(Oh yeah yeah yeah yeah, yeah)
But that's just how I feel,
That's just how I feel
Trying to reach the things
that I can't see
www.RentAnAdviser.com