Lately, I've been, I've been losing sleep
Dreaming about the things that we could be
But baby, I've been, I've been praying hard,
Said, no more counting dollars
We'll be counting star,
yeah we'll be counting star
I see this life like a swinging vine
Swing my heart across the line
And my face is flashing signs
Seek it out and you shall find
Old, but I'm not that old
Young, but I'm not that bold
I don't think the world is sold
I'm just doing what we're told
I feel something so right
Doing the wrong thing
I feel something so wrong
Doing the right thing
I could lie, coudn't I, could lie
Everything that kills me makes me feel alive
Lately, I've been, I've been losing sleep
Dreaming about the things that we could be
But baby, I've been, I've been praying hard,
Said, no more counting dollars
We'll be counting star
Lately, I've been, I've been losing sleep
Dreaming about the things that
we could be
But baby, I've been, I've been
praying hard,
Said, no more counting dollars
We'll be, we'll be counting stars
I feel the love and I feel it burn
Down this river, every turn
Hope is a four-letter word
Make that money, watch it burn
Old, but I'm not that old
Young, but I'm not that bold
I don't think the world is sold
I'm just doing what we're told
I feel something so wrong
Doing the right thing
I could lie, could lie, could lie
Everything that drowns me
makes me wanna fly
Lately, I've been, I've been
losing sleep
Dreaming about the things that
we could be
But baby, I've been, I've been
praying hard,
Said, no more counting dollars
We'll be counting stars
Lately, I've been, I've been
losing sleep
Dreaming about the things that
we could be
But baby, I've been, I've been
praying hard,
Said, no more counting dollars
We'll be, we'll be counting stars
Take that money Watch it burn
Sink in the river The lessons are learnt
Everything that kills me makes
feel alive
Lately, I've been, I've been
losing sleep
Dreaming about the things that
we could be
But baby, I've been, I've been
praying hard,
Said, no more counting dollars
We'll be counting stars
Lately, I've been, I've been
losing sleep
Dreaming about the things that
we could be
But baby, I've been, I've been
praying hard,
Said, no more counting dollars
We'll be, we'll be, counting stars
Take that money Watch it burn
Sink in the river The lessons are learnt
www.RentAnAdviser.com